Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers
1913-1973
75026
Hoover Institution Archives
61 manuscript boxes, 6 oversize boxes, 1 card file box, 1 envelope, and 1 motion picture film reel (26.8 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, clippings, and serial issues, relating to Jewish refugees from Nazi Germany, postwar German and Austrian restitution payments to Jewish war victims, German-Israeli relations, the conditions of Jews throughout the world, and civil liberties in the United States and Germany.
Grossmann, Kurt R. (Kurt Richard), 1897-1972
Access
Boxes 1-68 closed; microfilm use copy available.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (83 reels).
Biographical Note
1897, May 21 Born, Berlin, Germany.
1926-1933 General Secretary, Deutsche Liga fuer Menschenrechte.
1933, February 28 Fled from Germany to Prague.
1933, August 30 Expatriated.
1933-1938 Director, Demokratische Fluechtlings-fuersorge, Prague.
1935 Participated in effort to nominate Carl von Ossietzky for the Nobel Peace Prize.
1939 Emigrated to the United States.
1943 Author, Peace and the German Problem.
1944 Co-author (with Arieh Tartakower), The Jewish Refugee.
1954 Author, Germany's Moral Debt.
1957 Author, Die unbesungenen Helden (The unsung heroes).
1958 Author, Germany and Israel.
1961 Co-editor and contributor, Der Friede: Festgabe fuer Adolf Leschnitzer (Peace: presentation for Adolf Leschnitzer). U.S. correspondent for Vorwaerts, publication of the Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands, and other newspapers in Europe and Israel.
1963 Author, Ossietzky: ein deutscher Patriot (Ossietzky: a German patriot), awarded the Albert Schweitzer book prize.
1967 Author, Die Ehrenschuld: Kurzgeschichte der Wiedergutmachung (Debt of honor: short history of restitution).
1969 Author, Emigration: Geschichte der Hitler Fluechtlinge, 1933-1945 (Emigration: history of the refugees from Hitler's Germany).
1970 Co-editor and contributor, Gegenwart im Rueckblick: Festgabe fuer die juedische Gemeinde zu Berlin 25 Jahre nach dem Neubeginn (The present in retrospect: presentation for the Jewish community in Berlin 25 years after its re-establishment).
1971 Participated in effort to nominate Willy Brandt for the Nobel Peace Prize.
1972 Died, Miami, Florida.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, clippings, and serial issues, relating to Jewish refugees from Nazi Germany, postwar German and Austrian restitution payments to Jewish war victims, German-Israeli relations, the conditions of Jews throughout the world, and civil liberties in the United States and Germany.
Austria.; Civil rights--Germany.; Civil rights--United States.; Germany (West)--Foreign relations--Israel.; Germany.; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Israel--Foreign relations--Germany (West); Israel.; Jews--Austria.; Jews--Germany.; Jews--Legal status, laws, etc.; Moving-pictures.; Refugees.; Restitution and indemnification claims (1933- ); United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Jews.; World War, 1939-1945.
- MICROFILM REEL CONTENT GUIDE
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1913-1972. (Box 1-5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical data and writings, correspondence, clippings and notices of speeches relating to the life of Kurt R. Grossmann, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Address lists, Holographs and typescripts., c. 1938-1970. (Reel 1, Folder 1: 1-3)
  - Albert Schweitzer book prize, Letters of congratulations., 1963. (Folder 1: 4, Reel 1)
  - Bibliography, Typescript (carbon copies)., c. 1949. (Reel 1, Folder 1: 5)
  - Biographical sketches, Holographs and typescripts., c. 1942-1967. (Reel 1, Folder 1: 6)
  - Birthday celebrations. Newspaper clippings, letters of congratulations, and invitations.
    - 50th birthday celebration., 1947 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 7)
    - 60th birthday celebration., 1957 (Reel 1, Folder 1: 8-9, Reel 2)
    - 60th birthday celebration., 1957 (Folder 2: 1, Reel 2)
    - 65th birthday celebration., 1962 (Reel 2, Folder 2: 2-3)
    - 70th birthday celebration., 1967 (Reel 2, Reel 3, Folder 2: 4-7)
    - 75th birthday celebration., 1972 (Folder 3: 1, Reel 3)
  - Book lists, Typescripts., c. 1937/1970. (Folder 3: 2, Reel 3)
  - Demokratische Fluechtlingsfuersorge, Newspaper clippings and typescript., 1938. (Folder 3: 3, Reel 3)
  - Expatriation, Printed material., 1933. (Folder 3: 4, Reel 3)
    Includes Gesamtverzeichnis der Ausbürgerunglisten 1933-1938
  - Family documents, Handwritten and typescript copies., 1913-1972. (Reel 3, Folder 3: 5)
  - Funeral, 1972.
    Correspondence and newspaper clippings relating to the death of Kurt R. Grossmann.
    - General. (Folder 3: 6, Reel 4)
    - Eulogies. (Folder 3: 7, Reel 4)
    - Letters of condolence. (Reel 4, Folder 3: 8-9)
  - Germany, visits to.
    Letters and reports relating to Grossmann's study trips to West Germany. Holographs and typescripts.
    - 1952. (Folder 3: 10, Reel 4)
    - 1953. (Folder 3: 11, Reel 5)
    - 1956. (Reel 5, Folder 3: 12)
    - 1957. (Folder 3: 13, Reel 5)
    - 1959. (Folder 3: 14, Reel 5)
    - 1964. (Folder 4: 1, Reel 16)
    - 1967. (Reel 5, Folder 4: 2)
    - 1970. (Reel 5, Folder 4: 3)
  - Interviews, Typescripts., 1956-1958. (Reel 5, Folder 4: 4)
  - Membership cards, Printed copies., 1926-1971. (Folder 4: 5, Reel 5)
  - Miscellaneous. (Folder 4: 6, Reel 5)
  - Olean, N.Y., visit to, Correspondence, newspaper clippings, and printed material., 1962. (Folder 4: 7, Reel 5)
  - Press notices, Newspaper clippings., 1942-1969. (Folder 4: 8-13, Reel 5)
    - General.
    - 1946. (Folder 4: 14, Reel 5)
    - re Berlin Wall., 1961 (Reel 5, Folder 4: 15)
    - 1965. (Folder 4: 16, Reel 5)
    - 1966. (Folder 4: 17, Reel 6)
    - re Veit Valentin., 1967 (Reel 6, Folder 4: 18)
  - Publicity, 1930-1970.
    Announcements for lectures given by Grossmann. Printed and mimeographed copies.
    - undated (Reel 6, Folder 4: 19)
    - 1930-1956 (Reel 6, Folder 4: 20)
    - 1958-1959 (Reel 6, Folder 4: 21)
    - 1960-1962 (Reel 6, Folder 4: 22)
    - 1963-1971 (Reel 6, Folder 5: 1)
  - Reference, letters of, Typescript copies., 1938-1950. (Reel 6, Folder 5: 2)
  - Restitution for the Grossmann family, 1951-1966. (Reel 7, Reel 6, Folder 5: 3-13)
    Correspondence relating to restitution payments from the West German government. Typescript copies.
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1936-1972. (Box 5-16)
  Correspondence of Kurt R. Grossmann, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Unidentified. (Folder 5: 14-21, Reel 7)
  - General.
    - ABC. (Folder 5: 22, Reel 7)
    - DEF. (Folder 5: 23, Reel 7)
    - GHI. (Folder 5: 24, Reel 7)
    - JKL. (Folder 6: 1, Reel 7)
    - MNO. (Folder 6: 2, Reel 7)
    - PQR. (Folder 6: 3, Reel 7)
    - STU. (Folder 6: 4, Reel 7)
    - VWXYZ. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 5)
  - Abendzeitung, Munich, 1964/1969. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 6)
  - Aicher-Scholl, Inge, 1957-1971. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 7)
  - Alberti, Frederic M., n.d. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 8)
  - Albrecht, Gertrude, 1956-1971. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 9)
  - Alexan, Friedrich, 1942. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 10)
  - Allgemeine unabhaengige Wochenzeitung der Juden in Deutschland, 1962-1971. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 11)
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees, 1938-1939. (Folder 6: 12, Reel 8)
  - American Federation of Jews from Central Europe, 1961-1963. (Folder 6: 13, Reel 8)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1970. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 14)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1948-1950. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 15)
  - Anfanger, Charlotte, 1959-1963. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 16)
  - Arani Verlag, 1957-1971. (Folder 6: 17, Reel 8)
  - Arbeidernes Justisfond, 1938-1939. (Folder 6: 18, Reel 8)
  - Arndt, Adolf, 1956. (Folder 6: 19, Reel 8)
  - Arndt, Klaus Dieter, 1967-1972. (Folder 6: 20, Reel 8)
  - Atlantik-Bruecke, 1964. (Folder 6: 21, Reel 8)
  - Aufbau, 1950-1972. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 22)
  - Axel Springer Verlag, 1967-1971. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 23)
  - Bacharach, Salli, 1970. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 24)
  - Badt, Heinz, 1969. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 25)
  - Bahr, Egon, 1968. (Folder 6: 26, Reel 8)
  - Balabkins, Nicholas, 1968-1971. (Folder 6: 27, Reel 8)
  - Barzel, Rainer, 1965-1969. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 28)
  - Bauch, Botho, 1971. (Folder 6: 29, Reel 8)
  - Baum, Karl, 1970-1971. (Folder 6: 30, Reel 8)
  - Baum, Phil, 1969. (Folder 6: 31, Reel 8)
  - Baum, Walter, 1960-1967. (Folder 6: 32, Reel 8)
  - Bayerischer Rundfunk, 1956-1970. (Folder 6: 33, Reel 8)
  - Becker, Maximilian, 1966. (Folder 6: 34, Reel 8)
  - Beer, H. Rainer, 1970. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 35)
  - Belschner, Jacob, 1969-1970. (Folder 6: 36, Reel 8)
  - Benes, Eduard, 1934. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 37)
  - Bental, Otto, 1972. (Reel 8, Folder 6: 38)
  - Berendson, Walter A., 1970-1971. (Folder 6: 39, Reel 8)
  - Berger, David, 1959-1970. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 1)
  - Bertlet, Hartmut, 1963. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 2)
  - Bernstein, Philip S., 1951-1952. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 3)
  - Bilin, Lucy, n.d. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 4)
  - Bill, G., 1959-1962. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 5)
  - Birbach, Jerry, 1970. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 6)
  - Biss, Andreas, 1963-1970. (Folder 7: 7-10, Reel 9)
  - Blaustein, Jacob, 1950-1967. (Folder 7: 11, Reel 9)
  - Bloom, Sol, 1946. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 12)
  - Blumenthal, L. Roy, 1968. (Folder 7: 13, Reel 9)
  - B'nai B'rith, Munich, 1970. (Folder 7: 14, Reel 9)
  - Boenheim, Flora, 1956-1964. (Folder 7: 15, Reel 9)
  - Boletin informativo, 1965-1971. (Folder 7: 16, Reel 9)
  - Botstiber, Melanie B., 1969. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 17)
  - Brandt, Willy, 1957-1972. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 18-21)
  - Brann, Henry, 1970-1972. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 22)
  - Brecht, Arnold, 1960. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 23)
  - Brinkmann, Georg, 1971. (Folder 7: 24, Reel 9)
  - Bruegel, J. W., 1969. (Folder 7: 25, Reel 9)
  - Budzislawski, Hermann, 1938. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 26)
  - Bund der Verfolgten des Naziregimes, 1962-1971. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 27)
  - Bund freie Presse und Literature, 1938. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 28)
  - Cahn, Lucy, 1967-1971. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 29)
  - Cerny, Bohumil, 1968-1969. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 30)
  - Clark, Ronald W., 1970-1972. (Folder 7: 31, Reel 9)
  - Clay, Lucius, 1948. (Folder 7: 32, Reel 9)
  - Clemens, Walter, 1969. (Folder 7: 33, Reel 9)
  - Cohn, Toni, 1971. (Folder 7: 34, Reel 9)
  - Congress Bi-Weekly, 1971. (Folder 7: 35, Reel 9)
  - Dam, Henrik G. van, 1963-1971. (Folder 7: 36, Reel 9)
  - Debus, Uta, 1963-1964. (Folder 7: 37, Reel 9)
  - Delman, Michael N., 1970. (Folder 7: 38, Reel 9)
  - Deutsch, Maria, 1966. (Folder 7: 39, Reel 9)
  - Deutsche Friedensgesellschaft, 1948-1950. (Folder 7: 40, Reel 9)
  - Deutsche Presse Agentur, 1971. (Folder 7: 41, Reel 9)
  - Deutsches Dokuentationszentrum, 1969. (Folder 7: 42, Reel 9)
  - Deutschkron, Inge, 1969-1970. (Folder 7: 43, Reel 9)
  - Dohnanyi, Klaus von, 1971. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 44)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1971. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 45)
  - Drewes, Gertrud, 1971. (Folder 7: 46, Reel 9)
  - Dukas, Helen, 1964-1971. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 47)
  - Ebeling, 1964-1971. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 48)
  - Eggebrecht, Axel, 1963. (Reel 9, Folder 7: 49)
  - Eisinger, Ernst, 1966-1969. (Reel 10, Folder 7: 50)
  - Elsberg, Heinz, 1961-1971. (Reel 10, Folder 7: 51)
  - Encyclopaedia Judaica, 1967-1970. (Folder 7: 52, Reel 10)
  - Ender, Wolfram, 1971. (Folder 7: 53, Reel 10)
  - Europaeische Verlagsanstalt, 1969-1973. (Folder 8: 1-3, Reel 10)
  - Fabian, Hans-Erich, 1967-1973. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 4)
  - Fabian, Walter, 1964, 1970-1971. (Folder 8: 5, Reel 10)
  - Fechenbach, Irma, 1947. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 6)
  - Ferencz, Benjamin B., 1953-1970. (Folder 8: 7, Reel 10)
  - Fischer, Alfred Joachim, 1965-1972. (Folder 8: 8, Reel 10)
  - Fischer, Samson, 1966-1971. (Folder 8: 9, Reel 10)
  - Fischer Buecherei, 1960-1964. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 10-11)
  - Fiss, Emil, W., 1970-1971. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 12)
  - Floerscheimer, Walter D., 1961-1963. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 13)
  - Fonds zur Hilfeleistung an politisch Verfolgte, 1972. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 14)
  - Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1970-1971. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 15)
  - Frankfurter Hefte, 1969. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 16)
  - Frankfurter Rundschau, 1953, 1969-1970. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 17)
  - Freedman, Paul W., 1956. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 18)
  - Frei, Bruno, 1964. (Folder 8: 19, Reel 10)
  - Freund-Hoppe, Marta, 1948-1950. (Folder 8: 20, Reel 10)
  - Fried, John, H. E., 1955-1958. (Folder 8: 21, Reel 10)
  - Friedle nder, Walter, 1969-1971. (Folder 8: 22, Reel 10)
  - Friedrich, Otto, 1970. (Folder 8: 23, Reel 10)
  - Fritsch, Franz, 1969-1970. (Folder 8: 24, Reel 10)
  - Fritsch, Otto Ernst, 1959-1972. (Folder 8: 25, Reel 10)
  - Frolich, Alice, 1971. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 26)
  - Froelich, Rose, 1969-1980. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 27)
  - Fuelster, Hans, 1948. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 28)
  - Galinski, Heinz, 1962-1971. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 29)
  - Gehrke, 1945-1960. (Folder 8: 30, Reel 10)
  - George, Jeanette, 1970. (Folder 8: 31, Reel 10)
  - Germany, West. (Reel 10, Folder 8: 32-38)
    - General (correspondence with various government agencies), 1947-1972.
    - Auswaertiges Amt (state department, 1967-1971. (Reel 11, Folder 8: 39)
    - Consulate, New York, 1956-1972. (Reel 11, Folder 8: 40)
    - Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1957-1971. (Folder 9: 1, Reel 11)
    - Entschaedigungsamt, Berlin (restitution office), 1963-1970. (Folder 9: 2, Reel 11)
    - German Information Center, New York, 1962-1972. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 3)
  - Gesellschaft fuer christlich-juedische Zusammenarbeit, 1969. (Folder 9: 4, Reel 11)
  - Gibson, Kenneth A., 1970. (Folder 9: 5, Reel 11)
  - Gilbert, Walter, 1944-1971. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 6-9)
  - Glaserfield, Hans, 1942-1971. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 10)
  - Goethe House, New York, 1967-1972. (Folder 9: 11, Reel 11)
  - Goldenburg, Norbert, 1971. (Folder 9: 12, Reel 11)
  - Goldmann, Nahum, 1953-1972. (Folder 9: 13-14, Reel 11)
  - Goldstein, Moritz, 1955-1971. (Folder 9: 15, Reel 11)
  - Gottgetreu, Erich, 1970. (Folder 9: 16, Reel 11)
  - Goetting, Martha, 1966. (Folder 9: 17, Reel 11)
  - Gottschalk, Emil, 1957-1970. (Folder 9: 18, Reel 11)
  - Greenburger, Sanford Jerome, 1951-1952. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 19)
  - Grossmann, Elsa, 1952-1964. (Folder 9: 20-22, Reel 11)
  - Grueber, Heinrich, 1962-1971. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 23)
  - Gruendgens, Gustaf, 1961. (Folder 9: 24, Reel 11)
  - Gumbel, E., 1959-1963. (Folder 9: 25, Reel 11)
  - Gussmann, Walter, 1938-1939. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 26)
  - Habelt, G., 1970. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 27)
  - Hagedorff, Allan O., 1968-1971. (Folder 9: 28, Reel 11)
  - Hamburger, Ernest, 1968-1971. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 29)
  - Hammer, Walter, 1947-1964. (Reel 11, Folder 9: 30)
  - Harding, Felix, 1967-1972. (Folder 9: 31, Reel 11)
  - Harrison, Earl G., 1943-1954. (Folder 9: 32, Reel 11)
  - Hartogsohn, Naphtoli Hartog, 1970. (Folder 9: 33, Reel 11)
  - Heilbrun, Werner, 1970. (Reel 12, Folder 9: 34)
  - Heinemann, Gustav, 1967-1970. (Reel 12, Folder 9: 35)
  - Heinig, John, 1970. (Reel 12, Folder 9: 36)
  - Heintz, Georg, 1966-1972. (Reel 12, Folder 9: 37)
  - Hermann, Margarete, 1959-1972. (Folder 9: 38, Reel 12)
  - Herz, Peter, 1971. (Folder 9: 39, Reel 12)
  - Hessischer Rundfunk, 1959-1970. (Folder 10: 1-6, Reel 12)
  - Heuss, Theodor, 1963. (Folder 10: 7, Reel 12)
  - Hiller, Kurt, 1968-1971. (Reel 12, Folder 10: 8)
  - Hirsch, Felix, 1972. (Reel 12, Folder 10: 9)
  - Hirsch, Martin, 1961-1971. (Reel 12, Folder 10: 10)
  - Hirschberg, Max, 1950-1964. (Folder 10: 11, Reel 12)
  - Horkheimer, Max, 1964-1971. (Folder 10: 12, Reel 12)
  - Horn, Kurt, 1948. (Folder 10: 13, Reel 12)
  - Hoskova, Helga, 1968. (Folder 10: 14, Reel 12)
  - Huber, Frank L., 1967-1968. (Folder 10: 15, Reel 12)
  - Hupka, Herbert, 1971. (Reel 12, Folder 10: 16)
  - Institut fuer Zeitgeschichte, Munich, 1967-1970. (Reel 12, Folder 10: 17)
  - Institute of Jewish Affairs, 1969. (Reel 12, Folder 10: 18)
  - International Christian Committee for German Refugees, 1938. (Folder 10: 19, Reel 12)
  - International Rescue and Relief Committee, 1945. (Folder 10: 20, Reel 12)
  - Internationale Liga fuer Menschenrechte, 1949-1972. (Folder 10: 21-23, Reel 12)
  - Inter Nationes, 1969-1970. (Folder 10: 24, Reel 13)
  - Isenheim, Arnold, 1950. (Folder 10: 25, Reel 13)
  - Isolani, Gertrud, 1965-1971. (Folder 10: 26, Reel 13)
  - Israel.
    - Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1964. (Folder 10: 27, Reel 13)
    - Embassy, West Germany, 1967-1969. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 28)
  - Jacob, Walter, 1949-1950. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 29)
  - Javits, Jacob, 1967-1970. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 30)
  - Jedioth Chadashoth, Tel-Aviv, 1964-1972. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 31)
  - Jellinek, Gustav, 1954-1972. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 32)
  - The Jewish Agency, 1966-1971. (Folder 10: 33, Reel 13)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1940. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 34)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1939-1960. (Folder 10: 35, Reel 13)
  - Kagan, Saul, 1952-1965. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 36)
  - Kalisky, Betty, 1956-1971. (Reel 13, Folder 10: 37)
  - Kandel, Morris, 1967-1968. (Folder 11: 1, Reel 13)
  - Kanig, Hans, 1962. (Folder 11: 2, Reel 13)
  - Kantor, Siegfried, 1944. (Folder 11: 3, Reel 13)
  - Karsch, Walter, 1963. (Folder 11: 4, Reel 13)
  - Katz, Carl, 1969. (Folder 11: 5, Reel 13)
  - Katz, Theodor, 1970. (Folder 11: 6, Reel 13)
  - Katzenstein, Ernst, 1969-1971. (Reel 13, Folder 11: 7)
  - Kempner, Robert M.W., 1946-1973. (Reel 13, Folder 11: 8-11)
  - Kesten, Hermann, 1968-1973. (Reel 13, Folder 11: 12)
  - Kindler Verlag, 1960-1973. (Reel 13-14, Folder 11: 13-18)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1970-1971. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 19)
  - Korherr, Richard, 1959-1966. (Folder 11: 20, Reel 14)
  - Kowal, Oscar, 1970-1971. (Folder 11: 21, Reel 14)
  - Kraschutzki, Enrique, 1970. (Folder 11: 22, Reel 14)
  - Kreisselmeier, H., 1970. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 23)
  - Kressmann, Charlotte, 1969. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 24)
  - Kressmann, Willy, 1939. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 25)
  - Kreutzberger, Max, 1970-1971. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 26)
  - Kroll, Siegfried, 1963-1970. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 27)
  - Kuerschners Deutscher Literatur-Kalender, 1972. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 28)
  - Kuestermeier, Rudolf, 1969-1973. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 29)
  - Lamm, Hans, 1963-1969. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 30)
  - Landau, Edwin, 1962-1970. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 31)
  - Landau, Ernest, 1953-1969. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 32)
  - Landmann, Elisabeth, 1970-1972. (Folder 11: 33, Reel 14)
  - Lang, Joseph, 1947-1972. (Folder 11: 34, Reel 14)
  - Lania, Lucy, 1960-1972. (Folder 11: 35, Reel 14)
  - Lappuse, Martha, 1956. (Folder 11: 36, Reel 14)
  - Lasky, Victor, 1950. (Folder 11: 37, Reel 14)
  - Laumann, Kurt, 1970. (Folder 11: 38, Reel 14)
  - Lederer, Theodore I., 1969-1970. (Folder 11: 39, Reel 14)
  - Lehmann, Ingeborg, 1953-1960. (Folder 11: 40, Reel 14)
  - Lehmann-Russbueldt, Otto, 1948-1956. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 41)
  - Lemmer, Ernst, 1956. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 42)
  - Leiser, Clara, 1953. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 43)
  - Leo Baeck Institute, 1963-1972. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 44)
  - Leschnitzer, Adolf, 1956-1971. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 45)
  - Lewy, Fritz, n.d. (Reel 14, Folder 11: 46)
  - Liebig, Gerhard, 1948. (Folder 12: 1, Reel 14)
  - Likuski, Autje, 1970-1971. (Folder 12: 2, Reel 14)
  - Lindsay, John, 1970-1971. (Folder 12: 3, Reel 14)
  - Lochner, Hilde, 1942-1945. (Reel 14, Folder 12: 4)
  - Lochner, Louis, 1943-1955, 1970. (Folder 12: 5, Reel 14)
  - Loewenson, Franz, 1949-1956. (Folder 12: 6, Reel 14)
  - Lohe, Wilfriede, 1964. (Folder 12: 7, Reel 14)
  - Lothar Stiehm Verlag, 1970-1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 8-9)
  - Lowen, Ernest D., 1956. (Folder 12: 10, Reel 15)
  - Lowenstein, Ludwig, 1954-1967. (Folder 12: 11, Reel 15)
  - Luckner, Gertrud, 1956-1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 12)
  - Luenser, Albert, 1947-1948. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 13)
  - Luschnat, David, 1969-1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 14)
  - Lueth, Erich, 1963-1972. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 15)
  - Lynn, Fred L., 1950-1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 16)
  - Mann, Alfred, 1955. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 17)
  - Mann, Thomas, 1940. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 18)
  - Mannheimer, Morgen, 1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 19)
  - Mansfeld, Michael, 1968. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 20)
  - Marck, Claire, 1963-1971. (Folder 12: 21, Reel 15)
  - Marcus, Robert S., 1950. (Folder 12: 22, Reel 15)
  - Marcuse, Ludwig, 1954. (Folder 12: 23, Reel 15)
  - Marx, Betty, 1967-1971. (Folder 12: 24, Reel 15)
  - Marx, Werner, 1969-1971. (Folder 12: 25, Reel 15)
  - Mauritz, Else, 1936-1947. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 26)
  - Maussner, Angelika, 1970. (Folder 12: 27, Reel 15)
  - Mautner, Franz H., 1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 28)
  - May, Kurt, 1965-1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 29)
  - Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture, 1966-1968. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 30)
  - Messow, Babette, 1957-1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 31)
  - Metall, 1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 32)
  - Meyerowitz, Alfred, 1956-1971. (Folder 12: 33, Reel 15)
  - Mierendorff, Marta, 1962-1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 34)
  - Mineta, Helen, 1950. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 35)
  - Monat, 1969-1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 36)
  - Motzko, Ernst Bruno, 1965-1969. (Folder 12: 37, Reel 15)
  - Nansen-Hjelp for Statsrettlose, 1939. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 38)
  - Naor, Uri, 1953-1954. (Folder 12: 39, Reel 15)
  - Nau, Alfred, 1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 40)
  - Nehyba, Franz, 1948. (Folder 12: 41, Reel 15)
  - Nelke, Guenter, 1939-1963. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 42)
  - Neuberger, Josef, 1971. (Folder 12: 43, Reel 15)
  - Neue Gesellschaft, Die, 1969-1972. (Folder 12: 44, Reel 15)
  - Neue Weltbuehne, Die, 1947. (Folder 12: 45, Reel 15)
  - Neue Zuercher Zeitung, 1965-1971. (Folder 12: 46, Reel 15)
  - Neumann, Franz, 1955. (Folder 12: 47, Reel 15)
  - Neumann, Robert, 1969-1970. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 48)
  - Neumann, Stephan, 1939-1940. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 49)
  - The New Leader, 1945. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 50)
  - New School for Social Research., 1969-1971. (Reel 15, Folder 12: 51)
  - New York City Housing Authority, 1971. (Folder 12: 52, Reel 15)
  - New York Times, 1968-1971. (Folder 12: 53, Reel 15)
  - Norddeutscher Rundfunk.
    - n.d. (Folder 13: 1, Reel 16)
    - 1959. (Folder 13: 2, Reel 16)
    - 1960. (Folder 13: 3, Reel 16)
    - 1961. (Folder 13: 4, Reel 16)
    - 1962. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 5)
    - 1963. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 6)
    - 1964. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 7)
    - 1965. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 8)
    - 1967-1968. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 9)
  - Notgemeinschaft deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland, 1939. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 10)
  - Nuernberger Nachrichten, 1970. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 11)
  - Nussbaum, Max, 1961-1970. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 12)
  - Oehlschlager, Ernst, 1947-1948. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 13)
  - Oliver, Margaret, 1966-1967. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 14)
  - Oppenheimer, John, 1965-1972. (Folder 13: 15, Reel 16)
  - Oschilewski, W. G., 1956-1970. (Folder 13: 16, Reel 16)
  - Ossietzky-Palm, Rosalinda von, 1963-1965. (Folder 13: 17, Reel 16)
  - Oestreich, Paul, 1950. (Folder 13: 18, Reel 16)
  - Pergamenter, Walter, 1961. (Folder 13: 19, Reel 16)
  - Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences, New York, 1970. (Folder 13: 20, Reel 16)
  - Prager, Alfred, 1957-1964. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 21)
  - Preuss, Hans, 1966. (Folder 13: 22, Reel 16)
  - Prinz, Joachim, 1967-1972. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 23)
  - Puttkamer, Jesco von, 1967-1971. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 24)
  - Ray, Grace, 1961-1962. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 25)
  - Reclam, 1971-1972. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 26)
  - Reichenthal, Frank (Mrs.), 1971. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 27)
  - Reissner, Hanns G., 1970-1971. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 28)
  - Rheinischer Merkur, 1965-1972. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 29)